I think this is the most common question that
comes to me that if I have
employer's insurance then why do I need my
personal insurance, do I need it or
not and if yes then
why, today I will address this question
that if you have employee's insurance then
what should you do, I will give you five reasons why
you should take your standard health
insurance, then we will talk about how
you can buy your standard health
insurance along with
your employer's insurance, lastly we will talk about
how much sum in short should you actually
take because you have employer's insurance,
then how much sum in short should you take
on standard health insurance,
before starting the video I would
like to introduce myself, my name is
Goodwillin Kaur Checkup, I am a Certified
Financial Planner, every week I bring videos for you to
make your personal finances easy and happy.
Because the tagline of our company is also '
Creating a Wealth of Happiness' and a
quick reminder if you have
not yet subscribed to our channel, do
subscribe so that you get the right
information and the right time as it is going to be available now.
First we will talk about five reasons why
you have to take standard health policy,
unlike your employer's health
insurance. So the first strong reason is that
employer's insurance, that is not
permanent, that insurance is only till the time
you are employed, you do not know which
insurance policy will be there and this
insurance policy may change from time to time.
Whatever features you have, that means you are
dependent on respect. Else, it is
not a policy of your choice, it
is not insured of your choice and you do not have a front cover of your choice,
so it is important to have your standard
health insurance. Secondly,
note down the features and terms and conditions
that you want, meaning that those
features may be there, there may be room rent camping, there may be
some restrictions there.  If you do
n't have maternity coverage and you need it, then
you become dependent on someone else's insurance
tax. It may be a co-payment. Many times,
it happens that the premium in employer insurance
increases due to clean
and health and collection. So, to control the cost,
what the employer does is they add a co-payment
or negotiate the terms and conditions.
As you know, the
employer insurance group
insurance company negotiates the terms and conditions and
pick and choose the features.
It is a custom product. It is not a
retail standard product. If it is a custom product, then
some features will be added, some will not be added,
some additional ones will be added and so on. The
features of the product are not as per your choice. The
terms and conditions are your choice, it
may or may not be there, so it will
not be beneficial for you in any case. That means that tax is debtor,
but on top of that, it is
necessary to have a tax of your choice, in which there is no co-payment, in which there is no
room rent typing.
Thirdly, in the tax, note BN  So the
tax that I usually hear is employer tax.
Where will the ₹5 lakh
tax of ₹35 lakh be useful? The health inflation that you are seeing and the
treatment, there is a
health inflation of 15%,
14-15%, so in that your ₹3 lakh or ₹5 lakh
tax is not going to be useful in the future. That is why
your standard on health insurance
is necessary. Fourth, many times these people postpone this decision
that right now there is
no employee insurance, go to the employer and if there is
no employer insurance there then we will take it.
But do not make such a mistake, what
happens is your health condition, the
health condition that you have today due to IT bill note remains,
versus after 10 years the health condition will not
remain because of an lifestyle and habit,
kuch bhi lifestyle medicine bhi start ho jati
hai vich is BP, diabetes or any
chronic condition ho jati hai, then that
insurance company does not give policy at all.
So many people come to me who are young
They also do not get the policy
because of their existing conditions. If
everything is healthy today, your health is absolutely
good and you are fit, then you should take health insurance
today itself and not wait.
You will take it when the employment insurance ends. Fifth reason is sector
80d. Sector 80d. You all know that the
government pays tax to you.
If you are in the old tax regime, then you
get tax benefit in sector 80d.
If you are paying the premium of health insurance, then
you get a benefit of Rs. 25,000.
If you are paying the premium of your parents
and they are above 60 or 61 plus, then
you can also get a benefit of Rs. 50,000 for them under sector 80d. So the
government is also encouraging you to take
health insurance for yourself and focus on your
health but also on your
protection. So, according to
me, these five are solid
reasons due to which you should take your
standard on health insurance policy today.
You should take it, tell me where. If
you want to add any other reason to it, please
tell me in the comments. Now we will talk about
how you should take a health and health policy. You already have
employer tax, there is some tax or the other, which
means even if you take a minimum of Rs 2 lakh or 3 lakh, there is that tax. So
how should you take your health insurance policy? So usually, if
you already have this policy and its
features are comprehensive, which means you can take any room
or a single room, there is
no co-pay payment. It is a full tax policy which is
from the employer, you should check it. If there is a full tax, then
what will you do with it? You
can take a health insurance policy with a deductible option, which is a standard loan, which is
deductible. Annual aggregate is deductible, which
means the first amount which is annual aggregate
deductible, you
can clean it from your corporate tax and on top of that you can make your
standalone health insurance claim.
And for example, if you take a policy of Rs 20 lakh,
this is a hypothetical figure
because your annual premium  The date is
20000. You say that I am taking a deductible of 1 lakh in this, then
first ₹1 lakh will be recovered
from corporate tax and
after that your policy of ₹20 lakh will become
active which is stand alone, so
in lieu of that ₹1 deductible, the
insurance company gives you 50% discount on the premium, which
means instead of 20000
you have to pay only ₹10000 in this policy, the
policy will vary
how much discount you get on the deductible,
deductible is a good way, if you have
employer coverage then you get good discounts on standard on health
and insurance
and in future you are given the option to
remove this deductible,
subject to the terms and conditions, you should
check them, then you get the option only in future, so
if you have employee coverage
and you have decent coverage, comprehensive
coverage, then you can take a policy with deductible
and in future  Remove your adaptable.
Secondly, if you feel that this
is a very basic policy, which means it has co-
payment as well as room rent restriction
and you don't want to pay, you can either take it on a
smaller amount of adaptable, which means it is
your choice, you can take it without it,
but if you take a smaller amount, say
20,000, then also you get a 20-25% discount on the premium, that is, the
first 20,000
you will not get from standard insurance policies,
whether you pay from the operator or you
pay from your pocket,
you can take the policy with a small amount deductible as well,
and if your corporate policy is not
adequate, which means if it is not adequate, it is basic
coverage, then also you can
take it with a small amount deductible, you can remove it in the future
and do it, or if you want to
keep it completely separate, that
policy is an add-on, that is,
when you
want to keep your insurance policy in the company, then you can take it without deductible also.
That is your choice.
In fact, we have made some videos on deductible as well.
I will put the link of the same
in the description box. But based on the understanding,
you can take a call accordingly. You will
discuss how much you want to take. So,
as we discussed in the second point, you can
buy a policy with a deductible and if it is a
small deductible of Rs.
20 or Rs. 25,
you are getting a good discount with the deductible. So,
what is the difference in that, that you
can save more. Suppose your premium budget is that
you want to pay Rs. 25,000 per year,
but for Rs. 25,000, how much policy are you
getting? For example,
hypothetically, you are getting a policy of 20 lux.
With the deductible, you will get a policy of about 40 lux or
50 lux. So,
what will happen with that? Firstly, your tax will increase.
Initially, you have to pay a small amount, which
you can claim from your corporate as well.
But your tax amount will increase.  If it is done then
hire tax with deductible. If we
want to get a full figure of how much tax should be levied then it should be
3 to 5 times of your
annual income, meaning if you earn 10 lakh rupees a year,
many people earn
3-5 times of that, there should be a tax of 30 or 50 lakhs. If you
take more than that then nothing
like debt because you all know that
health and inflation in India is 14-15%, in which men's
treatment cost doubles every 5 years,
so the higher the tax, the better it will be for the
future. So this was the information from my side,
you buy your policy, otherwise your
employees' tax is your employer's
insurance, but it is necessary for you to buy your own insurance,
how will you buy it and how much tax will you
buy, whatever your feedback is, anything you
want to add on to it, you have some
experience, you have employment
insurance, it is not personal, if you have any such
experience which will help others, then
please share and comment.
In the area and you can shoot me if
you want to buy policy and if they have other
queries our WhatsApp number email id
is mentioned below you can connect and
quick reminder before going if
you have not subscribed to our channel yet do
subscribe so date you get the right
information and at the right time see you
in the next video with the next topic
thank you so match take care very often so
these are five regions five solid regions of mine
if you are taking a policy of 10 lakhs then the
more tax the better it will be for the future
[Music]
see you in the next video